<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skillset>
  <tree name="Blitz">
    <skill>
      <name>Flame Hammer</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>67</xPos>
          <yPos>1585</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>133</xPos>
          <yPos>1585</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>Your weapon crushes foes it strikes, creating 4 flaming splinters that seek out enemies within 5 meters. If available, a Charge is consumed to generate two additional blasts.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Creates 5 flaming splinters travelling 8 meters</tier>
        <tier>Creates 6 flaming splinters travelling 11 meters</tier>
        <tier>Creates 7 flaming splinters travelling 14 meters</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Seismic Slam</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>67</xPos>
          <yPos>661</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>133</xPos>
          <yPos>661</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>Your mechanically-assisted stomp stuns and burns all enemies in a 4 meter radius around you.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Radius increased to 6 meters</tier>
        <tier>Radius increased to 8 meters</tier>
        <tier>Radius increased to 10 meters</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Ember Hammer</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>133</xPos>
          <yPos>1783</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>199</xPos>
          <yPos>1783</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>You deliver a powerful sidelong swing which channels ember energy into a wide, 270 degree arc, destroying shields. Ember Hammer does not gain Charge.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Damage is amplified by 5% for every Charge</tier>
        <tier>Damage is amplified by 10% for every Charge</tier>
        <tier>Damage is amplified by 15% for every Charge</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Onslaught</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>397</xPos>
          <yPos>991</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>1</xPos>
          <yPos>1057</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>You leap forward, slamming your melee weapon into the ground. Foes at the point of impact are damaged and slowed significantly. Onslaught gains half of normal Charge.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Mana cost reduced by 20%</tier>
        <tier>Mana cost reduced by 40%</tier>
        <tier>Mana cost reduced by 60%</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Ember Reach</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>265</xPos>
          <yPos>859</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>1</xPos>
          <yPos>925</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>A focused surge of energy draws a foe into striking range. You gain a 20% chance to stun for 3 seconds for every Charge you have, but the skill itself neither gains nor expends Charge. </description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Mana cost reduced by 20%. Damage Taken effect lasts 4 seconds.</tier>
        <tier>Mana cost reduced by 40%. Damage Taken effect lasts 6 seconds.</tier>
        <tier>Mana cost reduced by 60%. Damage Taken effect lasts 8 seconds.</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Storm Burst</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>199</xPos>
          <yPos>397</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>265</xPos>
          <yPos>397</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>A blast from your pack rockets you swiftly forward, knocking back foes. 3 bolts of energy discharge from your suit on impact, striking remote enemies. Every enemy hit also recharges your mana by 5%, for up to 5 targets.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Increases bolt discharge to 6</tier>
        <tier>20% chance to immobilize foes</tier>
        <tier>Cooldown reduced to 1 second</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Emberquake</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>265</xPos>
          <yPos>1783</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>331</xPos>
          <yPos>1783</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>A huge overhand smash sends out 8 radiating magma fissures to seek and destroy your enemies.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Fire damage increased by 20%</tier>
        <tier>Fire damage increased by 40%</tier>
        <tier>Fire damage increased by 60%</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Heavy Lifting</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>397</xPos>
          <yPos>2443</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>1</xPos>
          <yPos>2509</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>Your skill with giant weaponry allows you to attack faster and adds a chance to stun your foes.</description>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Supercharge</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>331</xPos>
          <yPos>133</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>397</xPos>
          <yPos>133</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>When you hit foes with a melee weapon, you have a chance to direct excess energy into your weapon and then discharge it during attacks over the next 10 seconds. While supercharged you gain additional Charge.</description>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Coup-de-Grace</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>331</xPos>
          <yPos>1981</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>397</xPos>
          <yPos>1981</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>When you hit a stunned target, an electrical surge helps finish the foe off. This ability cannot trigger more than one time per second.</description>
    </skill>
  </tree>
  <tree name="Construction">
    <skill>
      <name>Healing Bot</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>397</xPos>
          <yPos>199</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>1</xPos>
          <yPos>265</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>You deploy a small drone that generates energy pulses, healing both you and your allies.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>The energy pulse also regenerates Mana</tier>
        <tier>The Engineer and allies also get a 8% Armor boost</tier>
        <tier>The Engineer and allies also get a 16% Armor boost</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Blast Cannon</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>331</xPos>
          <yPos>2245</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>397</xPos>
          <yPos>2245</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>You fire a long-range, piercing projectile from your cannon. At higher ranks, the blast leaves foes more susceptible to further fire and physical damage.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>25% chance to Blind foes for 4 seconds</tier>
        <tier>50% chance to Blind foes for 4 seconds</tier>
        <tier>75% chance to Blind foes for 4 seconds</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Spider Mines</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>265</xPos>
          <yPos>331</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>331</xPos>
          <yPos>331</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>You deploy a trio of spider drones that charge the nearest foes and explode in a 3 meter radius. Upgraded mines do 20% more damage with a 5 meter radius, a 2 second stun, and electric damage over time.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Mana cost reduced by 20%</tier>
        <tier>Mana cost reduced by 40%</tier>
        <tier>Mana cost reduced by 60%</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Gun Bot</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>1</xPos>
          <yPos>1387</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>67</xPos>
          <yPos>1387</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>You deploy a small drone that assaults your enemies with a hail of gunfire, firing 5 rounds per second. Each rank increases the bot's damage potential.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Firing range doubled. Summoning cooldown reduced to 2.5 minutes</tier>
        <tier>Shots pierce enemies. Summoning cooldown reduced to 2 minutes</tier>
        <tier>Triple-spread shots. Summoning cooldown reduced to 1.5 minutes</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Shock Grenade</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>265</xPos>
          <yPos>463</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>331</xPos>
          <yPos>463</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>You lob a grenade, which shocks and stuns enemies in a 4 meter radius. Consumes one Charge for two additional grenades.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Grenade shock radius grows to 5 meters</tier>
        <tier>Grenade stun time increased to 5 seconds</tier>
        <tier>Grenade shock radius grows to 6 meters and stun time increased to 6 seconds</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Fusillade</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>67</xPos>
          <yPos>1453</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>133</xPos>
          <yPos>1453</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>You unleash a continuous barrage of long-range, homing rockets from your cannon. Bursts of 2 rockets keep firing as long as the mouse button is held down.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>3 rockets are released per burst</tier>
        <tier>Rockets detonate in a 3 meter burst</tier>
        <tier>4 rockets are released per burst</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Sledgebot</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>199</xPos>
          <yPos>1321</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>265</xPos>
          <yPos>1321</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>You construct a powerful Sledgebot to pulverize your foes.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Sledgebot gains sweep attack</tier>
        <tier>Sledgebot gains smash attack</tier>
        <tier>Sledgebot gains rocket attack</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Bulwark</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>331</xPos>
          <yPos>2377</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>397</xPos>
          <yPos>2377</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>Your expertise with armor lets you get the most out of it, increasing its effectiveness, and reducing any damage that actually gets through.</description>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Fire and Spark</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>199</xPos>
          <yPos>1717</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>265</xPos>
          <yPos>1717</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>The spark to make things work ... and fire to make things die.. Each level adds 5% to all fire and electric-based damage inflicted by the Engineer.</description>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Charge Domination</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>331</xPos>
          <yPos>2113</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>397</xPos>
          <yPos>2113</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>When you slay an enemy, you have a chance to absorb enough energy to fill your Charge bar. This ability cannot trigger more often than once every three seconds.</description>
    </skill>
  </tree>
  <tree name="Aegis">
    <skill>
      <name>Shield Bash</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>67</xPos>
          <yPos>529</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>133</xPos>
          <yPos>529</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>You smash enemies in front of you, stunning them, slowing their attacks and knocking them back. Damage is equal to 5 times your shield's Armor value. Each Charge you currently have provides an additional 10% damage bonus. </description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Damage is increased to 7.5 times your Shield's Armor</tier>
        <tier>Damage is increased to 10 times your Shield's Armor</tier>
        <tier>Damage is increased to 12.5 times your Shield's Armor</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Forcefield</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>397</xPos>
          <yPos>1519</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>1</xPos>
          <yPos>1585</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>Your armor projects Ember energy, creating a forcefield around you, and a half-strength forcefield around allies. Once the forcefield absorbs its maximum damage it dissipates, removing all benefits.. Forcefield uses all available Charges to increase damage absorbtion by 50% per Charge.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Mana cost and casting time are reduced by 20%</tier>
        <tier>Allies receive a full strength shield</tier>
        <tier>Mana cost and casting time are reduced by 50%</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Overload</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>265</xPos>
          <yPos>991</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>331</xPos>
          <yPos>991</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>You overload your armor's circuits to project a nova of Ember energy, electrocuting up to 5 foes in a 6 meter radius around you. Overload uses all available Charges to increase its damage by 50% per Charge.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Up to 7 foes in an 8 meter radius are electrocuted</tier>
        <tier>Up to 9 foes in a 10 meter radius are electrocuted</tier>
        <tier>Up to 11 foes in a 12 meter radius are electrocuted</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Dynamo Field</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>331</xPos>
          <yPos>1849</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>331</xPos>
          <yPos>1849</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>You tap into your armor's energy to project an electrical burst in a 5 meter radius. This electrical surge generates charge for each enemy that is struck, up to five per field.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Field radius increased to 7 meters. Interrupt chance increased to 70%.</tier>
        <tier>Field radius increased to 9 meters. Interrupt chance increased to 90%.</tier>
        <tier>Field radius increased to 11 meters. Interrupt chance increased to 110%.</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Tremor</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>67</xPos>
          <yPos>133</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>133</xPos>
          <yPos>133</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>Discharging the energy from your suit into the earth causes a massive shockwave to expand outward, knocking back and weakening foes within 24 meters. Tremor only does the listed damage when it uses one Charge.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Adds a 20% chance for foes to Flee for 10 seconds</tier>
        <tier>Weakened foes also do 20% less physical damage</tier>
        <tier>All targets are stunned for 2 seconds</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Fire Bash</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>67</xPos>
          <yPos>1717</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>133</xPos>
          <yPos>1717</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>You channel a potent blast of energy through your shield up to 6 meters away. Damage is derived from your shield's Armor value. Initial physical damage is tripled and the blast range is increased to 9 meters with one Charge. </description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>Burn time increased to 5 seconds, doing more damage</tier>
        <tier>Damage arc widened by 40 degrees to hit more targets</tier>
        <tier>Targets take 50% additional fire damage while burning</tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Immobilization Copter</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>397</xPos>
          <yPos>331</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>1</xPos>
          <yPos>397</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>You deploy an immobilization drone which slows enemies within range of its beam. A maximum of 3 targets may be effected at once.</description>
      <tiers>
        <tier>A maximum of 5 targets may be affected at once</tier>
        <tier>Electrical damage inflicted while slowed</tier>
        <tier>Targets are intermittently interrupted </tier>
      </tiers>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Sword and Board</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>265</xPos>
          <yPos>199</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>331</xPos>
          <yPos>199</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>Your skill with a shield goes beyond "defense" and straight to "offense," adding some of your shield's armor value directly to your melee attacks as physical damage.</description>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Aegis of Fate</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>331</xPos>
          <yPos>1717</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>397</xPos>
          <yPos>1717</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>When foes attack you, your armor has a chance to generate a defensive "bubble" around you that prevents further damage. The amount of damage this shield can absorb is equal to 200% of your Armor plus 100. While the Aegis is active, you also get 50% Knockback Resistance.</description>
    </skill>
    <skill>
      <name>Charge Reconstitution</name>
      <icons>
        <inactive>
          <xPos>265</xPos>
          <yPos>2047</yPos>
        </inactive>
        <active>
          <xPos>331</xPos>
          <yPos>2047</yPos>
        </active>
      </icons>
      <description>When you use Charge for skills, you regain some of your Health.</description>
    </skill>
  </tree>
</skillset>
